<?xml version="1.0"?>
<!--
   Licensed to the Apache Software Foundation (ASF) under one or more
   contributor license agreements.  See the NOTICE file distributed with
   this work for additional information regarding copyright ownership.
   The ASF licenses this file to You under the Apache License, Version 2.0
   (the "License"); you may not use this file except in compliance with
   the License.  You may obtain a copy of the License at

       http://www.apache.org/licenses/LICENSE-2.0

   Unless required by applicable law or agreed to in writing, software
   distributed under the License is distributed on an "AS IS" BASIS,
   WITHOUT WARRANTIES OR CONDITIONS OF ANY KIND, either express or implied.
   See the License for the specific language governing permissions and
   limitations under the License.
-->
<document>

  <properties>
    <author email="">Conor MacNeill</author>
    <author email="stefan.bodewig@freenet.de">Stefan Bodewig</author>
    <title>Welcome</title>
  </properties>

<body>

  <section name="Apache Ant&amp;#x2122;">

    <p>Apache Ant is a Java library and command-line tool whose
		mission is to drive processes described in build files as targets
		and extension points dependent upon each other.
		The main known usage of Ant is the build of Java applications.
		Ant supplies a number of built-in tasks allowing to compile, assemble,
		test and run Java applications.
		Ant can also be used effectively to build non Java applications, for
		instance C or C++ applications. More generally, Ant can be used to
		pilot any type of process which can be described in terms of targets
		and tasks.
    </p>
	<p>
		Ant is written in Java. Users of Ant can develop their own
		&quot;antlibs&quot; containing Ant tasks and types, and are offered 
		a large number of ready-made commercial or open-source &quot;antlibs&quot;.
    </p>
	<p>
		Ant is extremely flexible and does not impose coding conventions or
		directory layouts to the Java projects which adopt it as a build tool.
	</p>
	<p>
		Software development projects looking for a solution combining build tool and
		dependency management can use Ant in combination with <a href="http://ant.apache.org/ivy/">Apache Ivy</a>.
</p>

        <p>The Apache Ant project is part of
          the <a href="http://www.apache.org/">Apache Software
          Foundation</a>.</p>
  </section>

  <section name="Apache Ant 1.9.3">
    <h3>December 29, 2013 - Apache Ant 1.9.3 Released</h3>
    <p>Apache Ant 1.9.3 is now available for download as source or
      binary from
      <a href="http://ant.apache.org/bindownload.cgi">http://ant.apache.org/bindownload.cgi</a>.</p>

    <p>Ant 1.9.3 contains several bug fixes and improvements compared to Ant 1.9.2.
      The main point of the release is a fix of the speed of the exec task. See bugzilla report 54128.</p>

  </section>

  <section name="Apache IvyDE 2.2.0">
    <h3>November 22, 2013 - Apache IvyDE 2.2.0 Released</h3>
    <p>The Apache IvyDE project is pleased to announce its 2.2.0 release.</p>
    <p>The Apache IvyDE Eclipse plugin integrates Apache Ivy's dependency management 
      into Eclipse. It lets you manage your dependencies declared in an ivy.xml in 
      your Java Eclipse projects, or any other kind of project which needs dependency 
      management. Apache IvyDE will contribute to the classpath of your Java project 
      or you can make it retrieve your dependencies directly into your project. Last 
      but not least Apache IvyDE offer editors of ivy.xml and ivysettings.xml files 
      with completion. Get some preview here: 
      <a href="http://ant.apache.org/ivy/ivyde/screenshots.html">http://ant.apache.org/ivy/ivyde/screenshots.html</a>
    </p>
    
    <h4>Major changes in this release</h4>
    <p><ul>
      <li>The API of IvyDE has been stabilized so that third party plugins can rely on it,</li>
      <li>while still not complete, and still not advertised as stable in Ivy, support of OSGi has been added,</li>
      <li>javadoc and source attachement can be edited now one by one,</li>
      <li>improved stability of the resolve process,</li>
      <li>improved logging for easier debugging.</li>
      </ul>
    </p>
    
    <h4>Compatibility</h4>
    <p><ul>
      <li>This release is expected to work with every version of Ivy 2.1 or superior. 
          The OSGi features require Ivy 2.3.0 or superior though.</li>
      </ul>
    </p>
    
    <p>This release is considered as stable. The beta of 2.2.0 has been out for a (too) long time.</p>
    <p>A more detailed release notes can be read there:
      <a href="http://ant.apache.org/ivy/ivyde/history/latest-milestone/release-notes.html">http://ant.apache.org/ivy/ivyde/history/latest-milestone/release-notes.html</a> <br/>
      Download the 2.2.0 release at:
      <a href="http://ant.apache.org/ivy/ivyde/download.cgi">http://ant.apache.org/ivy/ivyde/download.cgi</a> <br/>

      Or use directly the Apache IvyDE's updatesite:
      <a href="http://www.apache.org/dist/ant/ivyde/updatesite">http://www.apache.org/dist/ant/ivyde/updatesite</a> <br/>
      
      Issues should be reported to:
      <a href="https://issues.apache.org/jira/browse/IVYDE">https://issues.apache.org/jira/browse/IVYDE</a> <br/>
      
      More information can be found on the Apache IvyDE website:
      <a href="http://ant.apache.org/ivy/ivyde/">http://ant.apache.org/ivy/ivyde/</a>
    </p>  
  </section>

  <section name="Apache Ivy 2.3.0">
    <h3>January 21, 2013 - Apache Ivy 2.3.0 Released</h3>
    <p>Apache Ivy 2.3.0 is now available for download as source or binary (with and without
      dependencies) from
      <a href="http://ant.apache.org/ivy/download.cgi">http://ant.apache.org/ivy/download.cgi</a>.</p>

    <p>Key features of the 2.3.0 release are</p>
    <ul>
      <li>improved Ant support with some new Ant tasks and enhancements to existing tasks</li>
      <li>improved Maven2 compatibility</li>
      <li>some new resolvers</li>
      <li>numerous bug fixes and improvements as documented in Jira
        and in the release notes</li>
    </ul>

    <p>In addition, experimental OSGI support has been added to the Ivy core.</p>

    <p>For more information see
      the <a href="http://ant.apache.org/ivy/">Ivy home page</a>.</p>
  </section>

  <section name="Apache Compress Antlib 1.3">
    <h3>November 7, 2013 - Apache Compress Antlib 1.3 Released</h3>

    <p>The Apache Compress Antlib 1.3 is now available for download as <a
    href="http://ant.apache.org/antlibs/bindownload.cgi">binary</a> or
    <a href="http://ant.apache.org/antlibs/srcdownload.cgi">source</a>
    release.</p>

    <p>This release adapts to the 1.6 release of Apache Commons
    Compress and now adds support for the ARJ, LZMA and 7z
    formats.</p>
  </section>

  <section name="Documentation">

<p>
You can view the documentation for the current release (Apache Ant 1.9.0)
<a href="manual/index.html">online</a>
</p>

<p>
Comprehensive documentation is included in the source and binary distributions.
</p>

  </section>

  <!--section name="Nightly Builds">
    <p>
    If you wish to use the latest Ant features, you can try downloading a nightly
    build from <a href="http://brutus.apache.org/~nightlybuild/builds/ant/">here</a>
    </p>

  </section-->

  <section name="Get Involved">
<ul>
<li><a href="http://jakarta.apache.org/getinvolved/getinvolvedindex.html">Get Involved</a></li>
<li><a href="mail.html">Join Mailing Lists</a></li>
<li><a href="http://marc.info/?l=ant-dev&amp;r=1&amp;w=2">Search the Dev Mailing List</a>
</li>
<li><a href="http://marc.info/?l=ant-user&amp;r=1&amp;w=2">Search the User Mailing List</a>
</li>
</ul>



  </section>

</body>
</document>

